There's a great quote by I think Sam
Altman, right? Which is momentum is like
oxygen for a startup. You just feed off
of that momentum and it lets you put
more and more energy and more and more
cash if you need to into the company to
keep it growing. Within 45 days we had
crossed 100,000 ARR. Within 4 months we
crossed a million and then within 5
months we had crossed 2 million. And so
we just had more and more capital, more
and more confidence to reinvest into the
company to keep growing and keep working
with creators.
Hello, I'm your host David Bernard. And
with me today Revenue Cat CEO Jacob
Heding.
Our guests today are Brett Bauman and
Zack Hargett, co-founders of Coconote,
an AI-powered note-taking app that was
recently acquired by Quizlet. On the
Piecast we talk with Zack and Brett
about hitting a million dollars in ARR
in 4 months with no paid ads. Why trial
extensions beat discounts for saving
cancellations. And why you should be
hiring content creators, not
influencers. Zack, thanks so much for
joining us on the Piecast today. You got
it, David. Thanks for having me.
And Brett, nice to have you as well.
Happy to be here.
Jacob, back on the pod. With a with a
four-person pod my my commentary budget
is cut in half, so you may not hear that
much from me. But who wants to hear from
me anyway? These guys got the story to
tell, so.
>> They have a great story. Uh always fun
to have you on there for the color
commentary and uh feel free to interrupt
and interject to get get the color
commentary going. I'm going to kind of
spoil the ending, but I think this is
going to be in the title anyway. Brett
and Zack, you founded Coconote not too
long ago. Uh what, about 2 years ago?
And got it to 6.7 million in ARR and
then just sold to Quizlet. So quite a
story for a bootstrapped app to go so
quickly to that much ARR and then to
sell to such a big storied company in
the subscription app space. So I wanted
to kick it off just with the story of,
you know, when exactly was it and how
did Coconut come together? I think we
should take it back to 2022.
I had just shut down my
last startup which raised venture
capital. We were a consumer product
studio. We were building for
high school students and college
students. So, I really thought most
often of my little sister Emma, my step
sister Emma who was in high school and
then going into college right around
then.
So, it was 2022. I was tinkering around
with a Chrome extension which summarized
blog posts and YouTube videos because
frankly I didn't want to watch, you
know, an hour-long YouTube video. I
really just wanted like the two, three
sentence summary. And same thing with
blog posts, right? I came across a lot
of blog posts that I wanted to read, but
I didn't want to, you know, spend 30
minutes reading it. I just wanted the
summary to see if I wanted to dig
deeper.
And then Brett and I started tinkering
on a way to replace Siri with back then
GPT-4 in 2023. That's what I was going
to ask. So, the summarizations, those
were like the first like using LLMs to
do summaries which was like very very
novel and in '22, right?
>> Exactly. In '23, yeah. Yeah. Yeah, and
back then I believe it was still GPT-3
or some version of GPT-3.something.
>> Which worked, but it's nothing like what
we have today, right? Exactly. Yes,
[laughter]
for sure.
And
yeah, and Brett and I started tinkering
and I think we realized the power of
voice. We, you know, we're thinking
about summarization from the Chrome
extension that I was kind of hacking on.
And then we saw the the success of some
note takers that were more business
focused, but we didn't think people were
really taking it seriously. And so,
something that comes to my mind is a a
great Charlie Munger quote which is
simple ideas taken seriously. We kind of
came to this simple idea that this could
be great for college students and we
committed about two years ago. So, how
how did the two of you meet? I know you
you were both at Loom, but you didn't
overlap. So, how how did y'all meet and
how did how did you decide to build that
together? Yeah, so Zach was there before
I was and we basically just worked with
the same people
and I was on the mobile team. Zach did
all kinds of things at Loom being there
earlier than me and helped get the
mobile team started. But, Zach, I feel
like he was at like a the offsite one
time in LA. Zach was still coming to
offsites even though he didn't work
there anymore for some reason
>> [laughter]
>> Um some of our like mutual friends were
just like you guys should you guys
should meet and and we did and that's
kind of the how it started, yeah. That's
pretty cool. Jacob, is there a an
official policy if if I ever leave
Revenue Cat, do I get invited or or I
just get the boot? How does that work?
>> [laughter]
>> I don't think I would get the invite.
>> Nobody leaves Revenue Cat, that's the
thing. I didn't know you guys were Loom
alums. Uh obviously like massive fans,
still daily active. That's like such a
great interesting product, right? And it
makes a lot of sense like how that sets
you up for this project, right? It's
like summarization, note-taking, info
collection, and I think so much what
works great about Loom is like recording
a video you can do with QuickTime
Player, right? So, it's like in some
ways not that complicated, but Loom
makes it amazing product out of it,
right? And it's mostly the dressing,
right? And like the interfacing and like
the delivery. So, seems like there's a
real parallel here between, you know,
Coda note and and and Loom.
>> I think not a lot of people pick up on
that, but it is kind of Loom on easy
mode a little bit, recording audio and
uploading it and summarizing it and all
that. I just wanted to say my favorite
part of that night, absolutely. I think
it was at Elephante Brett in Santa
Monica and I was living like a couple
blocks away.
I won't say who to protect the innocent,
but someone was like, you know, looked
at Brett, looked at me, and was like,
"You two should meet and I'm not going
to be part of this. Like I'm going to
walk away because I I shouldn't know
about what you guys talk about.
>> That's why ex-employees are not invited
to off-sites. [laughter]
And so, I think the you know, the
universe if you put out startup vibes
and
you know, I don't know
the universe has a way of like making
things work out. Was it like you two
just really hit it off? Like these these
kind of founder stories are so
fascinating to me. Like how did two
people get together to build these
things? Like did you hit it off and then
like just build something together? Cuz
it sounds like you started building
before you actually built Coconut.
>> I might interject and just say like, you
know, obviously choosing co-founders is
like a super fraught thing and like
there's probably as many failures way
probably way more failures. Like most
startup early stage startup failures are
because of co-founder mismatch. Like
they sometimes get labeled other things,
but most of the time it's like
co-founders just weren't the right
combo. But like if you haven't worked
with somebody directly, I would say both
coming through the same alma mater or
the same organization certainly is like
the next best thing, right? Cuz you at
least know you've passed through like a
similar cultural filter. And also like
this is under under appreciated probably
is that you have a shared social
network, too, right? So you have like
outside of the financial alignment that
you have starting a company, you kind of
have an incentive not to screw the other
person because like you have similar
friends, right? So you like you don't
want to like mess up, you know, there's
there's more in it than just like the
time, right? There's like there's
there's a lot more connection, but it
it's super hard. I mean, I I don't want
to take over the podcast, but like I
think this is one of like the hardest
problems you can get right in starting a
company. I think there's kind of an
obvious complimentary skill set, right?
So Brett's background is making apps. My
background is making apps, but I'm not
especially technical. And so, me having
a design and product background, which
is what I did at Loom, and then as a
first-time founder realizing that if you
build it, they will not come. You have
to level up marketing. And so, I had to
get relatively decent at marketing in my
first startup. And then Brett with an
engineering background, but does so much
more than just engineering. I think
there was like a very obvious skill set
match. And the last thing I'll say
there, I'd be curious to hear what Brett
has to to say about this. I was mostly
like, you know, bugging Brett like,
"Hey, you know, hey, I have this idea.
I'd love to execute on this." And it's
him being like, "Hmm, well, maybe. I
don't know. We'll see." And then, you
know, eventually I bugged him to do one
and then the next and then we were just
kind of hacking and iterating and uh you
know, you know, thankfully he said yes.
So, you met, you hit it off, you figured
out you wanted to build something
together. You started tinkering with the
the Siri thing. Um but then tell us the
story of like when you realized like
Coconut was what you were going to build
and and how you got that to launch.
So, yeah, like I had mentioned, I'd been
building a lot for Emma, which is this
archetype that I had in my head, who's
my little sister. She was entering
college as a first year uh civil
engineering major. She still is a civil
engineer. So, we were thinking about
this. We were thinking a lot about how
can we, you know, summarize things, help
people learn. It's kind of a mishmash of
things. And then we arrived at Coconut.
There were some apps, not iOS apps, but
actually web apps that were out there on
the market doing a similar thing, but
they weren't taking it seriously. And
so, we just decided to execute on it. I
would say one of the things that we did
really, really well in hindsight is get
momentum as soon as possible. So, we had
a free trial from day one, but we were
in effect charging from day one. And
this is where, you know, this will play
out over the course of 2 years, David
Jacob, my fascination with checking the
revenue cat chart led to my wife to have
basically an intervention like, "Zach, I
think you have a problem. You check this
thing way too often." And it started
from basically day one because we were
trying to get, you know, momentum as
quickly as possible.
One way to look at momentum would be,
you know, something on Mixpanel, so like
usage and retention and very important
metrics, but there's nothing quite like
the dopamine high of realizing you're
creating something valuable to the world
and people are returning.
>> some of it, right? Like there's it's
hard to debate something that's being
done there. You can have a lot of
useless Mixpanel events, right? I've
always thought about this like I don't
intentionally in some ways don't want to
create fidget spinners for app founders,
right? Like some sort of just addiction.
But I also think that like hey, starting
and building a thing is intense and it
takes like a ridiculous amount of focus.
I think they're you know, much to the
detriment of the loved ones in your life
like checking that thing frequently is
not the worst thing in the world, right?
You have to stare at it every day. Was
it on the mobile app? Was that was that
because the mobile app I think came out
like halfway probably through I was
checking mobile web. I always had a full
web.
>> Yeah.
Yeah, the the the mobile app we we
released is like we we really weaponized
the the push notification addiction for
people. So anyway,
>> The widget even, yeah. Yeah, so this is
my official like Surgeon General's
warning to like, you know, you can
adjust your notification settings. You
don't have to get a notification and
check your thing every single time, but
you know, if you want to get a quiet
back Quizlet, maybe you do. I don't
know. How long were y'all working on it
before the April 2024 launch? Not super
long. We really wanted to scope it down
and launch something quickly and basic
and
I would say we achieved that and it like
sort of worked when we launched, you
know, but that was fine. There's a lot
about it honestly that looks the same
today as it did back then, which is
which is cool, but there was plenty of
like audio recordings getting lost and
and things like that. I guess you know,
it's it kind of feels like
this is one of those cases where a new
fundamental technology breakthrough.
Like this wouldn't have been an app you
could have built two years prior, right?
>> Totally, yeah.
And so you guys there's a huge first
mover's advantage, right? To getting
this and this would have been very
early. I remember around this time
looking for like casual note-taking
apps. Like there were some of them. I
forget like they're they've all like
cycled in and out already for yeah, like
the business context and I was like
"Man, it'd be nice if I could just set
this on the table, you know, when I'm
meeting with somebody in person." But,
yeah, how much of the how much of the
product improvement did you guys just
kind of get for free as like the models
progressed over those 2 years? Was it
Was it substantial? Did the product just
get better and cheaper to like operate
every every 2 months as the models
shipped or or was it like a lot of like
product development and fixing and
harness building? Oh, definitely both. I
mean, um you know, adding new features,
building things as new capabilities come
out and you can do
>> adapting to new new functionality. Yeah,
that Yeah, that's something we still do
today and that could be like building a
podcast uh that you can create. Um so,
you're kind of going from audio to text
to a summary and then back to audio
again in a shorter form. It'd be weird
to just listen to your lecture again,
right? Maybe? I don't know. That's funny
that there was demand for that. Yeah, I
think it gives people some safety
knowing that they can listen to it again
and like kind of zone out. Um or if they
want to replay something. Oh,
interesting. Like in the moment, people
are relaxed more. Like so, your app is
providing even when they're recording is
happening, you're providing value
because like they just have the peace of
mind that this is recorded, I can like
reference it later, like all of these
things. That's I guess obvious when you
say it, but like uh you think of app
value being delivered when an app is
used, right? And I guess the app is
being used at that point, but not in a
consumptive way, right? It's just be
It's doing its job passively, which is
cool. Right. Right. They're recording it
to really come back later and use what
they're getting right now. And it's
something we discovered from feedback
when like things would go wrong, you
know, and realize how much trust they're
giving us and like losing
it. Yeah.
>> a recording. Ouch. One of the best
things that we did, we just asked our
customers, "How would you describe
Coconote?" And
a great majority of them, it was
shocking how consistent this was. They
use Coconote to never miss a key detail.
And that is exactly what we put in the
first App Store preview screen. And so,
we I think one of the cool things that
we did with Coconote that I'd never done
in the past is listen to how your
customers describe your product and then
say that back to them. Right, there are
parallels here with even presidential
campaigns or government, you know,
position campaigns where you're
listening to what resonates with your
voter base and then you're saying it
back to them and I think that's in part
what a good marketer does.
That's fascinating. You know, I was just
thinking I actually had a version of
this in the '90s by having this amazing
study group. And it like what I did I I
didn't take notes. Two girls that I
would take every class with who were in
my same degree plan would take
meticulous notes and then we'd have
study groups together where I was like
chill listening, getting the bigger
concepts. They were taking notes. I was
more relaxed. And then our study
sessions were incredible. So like you
basically productized what I like lucked
into.
>> The classic group project hanger-on
monetized.
That's a good point though. It's You
know what I mean? Like like I mean Okay,
we talk about technology as like
deflationary, right? And like this is a
weird cuz you didn't pay to be part of a
study group, right? But you were lucky
to have that. You had to put energy to
put that together. It's difficult to
like find the right people and all that
stuff.
>> And I was bringing that up to the point
Brett was saying about like being able
to be relaxed during the session and
really listen. How's value? And like it
was valuable I wasn't just a hanger-on.
Like there was value to them for me to
like bring in contacts that they missed
because they were frantically taking
notes.
>> More brains are better than one whether
they run on a GPU or not.
>> Yeah. Yeah, so like that's what's so
cool is like and and for those who don't
aren't fully familiar with the product,
you record lectures like in high school,
college, and then it generates notes,
flashcards, quizzes, podcasts, games,
mind maps. Like it it generates all this
other content. And that's kind of what
we were doing in the study group in the
'90s.
>> With immense human effort, right? Which
which goes back to the deflationary
point, right? Like this technology just
like
free money. It's free real estate,
right? It's not free, obviously, but
very very cheap compared to like the
alternative. In those early days, what
were the key like insights and product
unlocks that that took you cuz it sounds
like you got some initial launch
traction, but what were those like
stepping stone moments that really kind
of like kept taking it to that next
level? Well, there's something that I
look for in consumer apps and trying to
understand why they've been so
successful and I I look at ones like
Larder or Alltrails or Strava and I
think that they all associate with like
a person's identity and then it's
something that they repeat frequently,
whether it's like running or
weightlifting. And to us
we we felt like we were capturing a
student's identity and going to class
and recording is something you do daily
or or a few times a week and
that was a big thing for us is trying to
find something that not just brings
value, but you could do it like in an
often and repeated way. Mhm. And you
build up this like also just this
corpus, right? Over time, right? Of
like, you know, especially like
subsequent classes like physics 1 2 3,
you now go back and reference physics 2.
You get all this like lock-in, right?
Which is they're really powerful in
terms of like retention and things like
that. Totally. Let's dive into growth.
How did you promote the launch and and
like what did traction look like out of
the gate? Yeah, on so on the growth
marketing side, we as I mentioned
before, we wanted to get traction.
There's a great quote by I think Sam
Altman, right? Which is momentum is like
oxygen for a startup. So, you want to
get as much momentum as soon as possible
and I know in some way I'm stating the
obvious, but there are very clear
tradeoffs. Right? In some cases, you
delay a launch, in some cases, you want
to perfect certain flows or perfect this
and that. Maybe you delay your launch
because of hiring, whatever.
I think the thing that we got really
really right from the start is we wanted
to get as much momentum as possible as
quickly as possible because momentum is
like oxygen. You just feed off of that
momentum and it lets you put more and
more energy and more and more cash if
you need to into the company to keep it
growing. So, in the early days it was
very obvious that we were going to use
social media to grow. I think we live in
this really interesting time where it
does not matter, generally speaking, how
many followers you have on short-form
video. It just matters if you make great
content. And so, we were trying
everything in the beginning. I have some
interesting stories. I don't know if I
should share them, but maybe we can
circle back to those early days. I mean,
it is like a true grind, right? And it
felt It feels good, right? To be part of
that game. But we were trying everything
we could and then I would say we worked
with
you know, easily 30 content creators of
various types in the early days. I would
say in the first 2 months.
And really three of them ended up making
a huge difference. One of them in
particular ran the main coconuts.app
account and generated hundreds of
millions of views. And I think I can
speak for Brett on this. We're very
lucky to have worked with him and
started working with him very early on
because he was a key part of our growth.
I know you guys don't want to say it,
but that was Mr. Beast.
>> If you're listening, we'd love to work
with you.
Uh I So, I was going to ask the model
there. Did Were you two ever dancing on
a Tik Tok? Did you like try any
first-party stuff yourself or did you go
straight to like, "Hey, we're just going
to like identify creators and have them
run and like that's in itself a process,
right? You're like trying different
creators and seeing who's good. How did
you How did you do it? I think Brett
danced on Tik Tok a couple of times and
then we got banned. And so, then we had
to figure out what else to do. It was
that good? Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah.
Um
So, we were not dancing on Tik Tok, but
we were definitely talking to a lot of
creators and studying like what's
working in the market.
Um
plenty of learnings I'd say on the on
the growth side. I don't know if this is
exactly relevant, but some some timeline
there within 45 days we had crossed
100,000 ARR, within 4 months we crossed
a million, and then within 5 months we
had crossed 2 million. And so we just
had more and more capital, more and more
confidence to reinvest into the company
to keep growing and keep working with
creators. Did you guys I mean this gets
into cash flow questions, but being
bootstrapped is I think it's a very
interesting. But like did you guys all
infuse cash in at all or were you I
guess you maybe by the way of not taking
any money out for yourselves or anything
like that? Like it's a flywheel, but
like you kind of there's like a minimum
buy-in to get scale for these. Like how
did you manage that? Yeah, it's a bit of
both of what you said, both of adding
some in and it's really slow in the
beginning on Apple. Like the delay of
when you get paid.
>> Yeah. And then minicasts.com/payouts. I
don't know if we have that set up yet,
but we're working on a product there.
It's really slow in the beginning,
especially if you then try to like
recognize your
revenue on an accrual basis and things
like that, which we had to learn and
It's a good way to descend into madness
is what that is. Yeah.
Yeah.
So yeah, we put in a a bit both in the
beginning to get things going and then
we really don't have even today much of
a free tier. You can use it a little bit
before you start a free trial, but that
helped as well.
>> Did cogs of produce like the LM calls
and like all that stuff does was that
material for you guys where you had to
consider it or was there enough of a
spread it didn't really matter? Not
really. I I think in the beginning we
didn't pay much attention to it. Always
felt like it'd be a good problem to have
if we end up having that problem and
then as we grew, you know, there's like
startup plans you can get on in the
first year, free credits, things like
that. And then as we rolled off of
those, we did make some decisions to be
more like cost efficient, but it was
overall totally fine.
>> Yeah, you have to figure in like the
giving away tokens at the beginning of
an experience is just part of your CAC
kind of, right? It's like you have to
give that away. I think too many people
again, it's like
yeah, I mean maybe maybe Zach having
gone through a venture back, you kind of
had the model of like capital equals
growth. Cuz I think I see sometimes with
bootstrap, and David's bootstrapped a
lot of things, but like because the um,
you know, dipping below the zero is into
your personal money, like there tends to
be a real hesitance, right? And that
it's almost it's it is almost easier to
bet I mean that's why a lot of people
always venture. I don't think it's a bad
reason to is like it's easier to spend
somebody else's money. It really is,
right? And there's good and bad things
about that. The good things being is
like you're a little bit your credit is
protected or whatever and all those, but
like, you know, from the bootstrapper
side, I think sometimes, you know, like
people are hesitant. And not even in
like I'm going to spend 100k my own
money. Like that's a big swing. But even
like, oh, I can't even ship a product
with negative gross margins or even like
even like risk my gross margins cuz oh
my god, what's going to happen, right?
And I think that can make you you can
make some really sub-optimal decisions,
right? If you're too concerned about it
way too early. Almost everything gets
cheaper at scale, right? Like as you get
bigger, one, you figure out how to make
it cheaper. Models are deflationary,
like our models are getting cheaper. So
even like today's functionality will
just be half the cost in a year. When
the time comes, yeah, it's it's a flip
side in computer science, they always
say no premature optimization. That's
totally true in companies, too. Like
don't don't optimize at the beginning.
So that's really interesting. So you
guys had like very low COGS, maybe
higher than like an app that didn't have
any AI like backing, but it's not not
something that was a concern. And then
you just you just started the flywheel
with a little bit of your own cash to
like get it going and then and then did
it just was it just like pull out,
reinvest, pull out, reinvest like cycle
all the way up? Was it was it fairly
smooth or how did the how did the
scaling go? Yeah, yeah, I would say so.
Um, we were able to just uh continue
working out of the the App Store
revenue, Stripe as well. We have an
Android app now. And
one interesting thing is that like the
the audio transcription costs are
actually more than the LLM generally.
And so that's like one that might be
surprising. But even there, like the
local models are getting really good.
And I think that if we were starting
from scratch, we could probably use
those.
>> Yeah, I mean, I guess it's like you only
need you need good transcription
quality, not like perfect, maybe, right?
Like especially if the LM is probably,
you know, it's going to know it's going
to know the professor didn't say fish,
right? Or something like that. It's
going to do a pretty good job of like
fixing that, I would imagine. Jacob, one
one thing to add on to this in terms of
the finances is that we were very
mindful of the financial, you know,
structure from basically day one. We
knew we'd have to invest some up front.
And it was, you know, around 10,000,
maybe each, that we had to invest up
front to get things off the ground. But
pretty much every month from inception
to the acquisition, we were around 50%
EBITDA margins. And so we really tried
to be lean. And then to your point
around raising or reinvesting,
there are absolutely trade-offs. One of
the reasons why I think we're so excited
to to now be under Quizlet is that we
can think longer term, right? We we can
make longer term decisions without this,
you know, make-believe 50% EBITDA. Yeah,
exactly. And so I think your ability to
think long-term is definitely influenced
by your capital structure, your capital
situation. And so I'm very happy to have
had that. And then on the other side of
it, right? It is really nice to have the
cash flow. So that financial discipline,
I think led us to have cash flow kind of
throughout, which was nice. Let's go
back to process, though, cuz I think a
lot of folks will be interested. So you
each put in around 10K. How did you
reach out to those first creators? Were
you just finding people on TikTok and
then DMing them? And, you know, were
those early ones paid? Did you do any
kind of referral? Like how did you get
that flywheel going? Cuz so many people
listening to this podcast, you know,
trying to figure that out. It was an
absolute grind in the beginning, because
you're just trying to find the channel
that works, right? And then you just
want to exploit may not be the right
word, but you want to double down and
you really want to spam more or less
that channel until you reach the limit.
We were reaching out all the above,
David. So, we were reaching out to
creators through if they had an email in
their bio. Uh funny observation here. If
you reach out to a content creator, I
have my opinions on influencers that we
can circle back to, but if you reach out
to a content creator and their email is,
you know, it's @sunsetagency.com
or something, any agency-sounding,
you're too late. Those agencies exist to
eliminate the alpha that you are trying
to create, okay? So, they are almost
always going to take more than they give
in terms of the value that they provide
to the company. There are always
exceptions, 100%, but generally
speaking, that's been my observation.
>> a lot of like mid-tier creators, too,
who like hear, "Oh, I have an agency."
And they get it and it's actually like
value-destructive for them. Totally.
Yeah, absolutely. If they have a Gmail
in their bio and they have, you know, 5,
10K followers, good engagement, that's
great. That's a really nice sweet spot.
And these numbers are very flexible, but
you know, whenever social media switched
over from a follower graph to an
interest graph and with a For You page
and algorithmic distribution, the number
of followers you have matters less and
less, right? The quality of the content
you create matters a ton. So, in It's
Scout, my last startup, the product
studio,
our first TikTok got 8 million views.
We'd never posted to the account before,
but we got 8 million views. It drove
150,000 sign-ups over a 2-day period. I
think at that time, this was 2021, if we
were an app not a website, I think we
would have been number one in in the App
Store. And so, I learned the value of
great content posted on TikTok at that
time. And so, we knew that that would be
the case. It was just a matter of how do
we get there? So, that's what you meant
about content creator. And you I I
noticed you chose your words very
carefully there. Content creator, not
influencer. So, the strategy wasn't to
find an influencer who had an audience.
The strategy was find a content creator
who produces great content. 100%. Yeah,
couldn't have said it better myself.
>> One of the struggles with with UGC and
this playbook is generating content that
converts versus generating content that
just gets a bunch of views. And then
depending on how you're paying the
creators, you know, if you're paying on
a view basis, they can really rack up
the bill, you know, doing just funny
TikToks that get attention, but then
don't convert. How did you address that
both, you know, financially and then
also in kind of learning what did
convert and kind of incentivizing that
kind of content? Yeah, a couple of
things come to mind. One is being
hands-on with the content creation team.
So, today our content team is about 25
people, 25 part-time creators that are
all contractors. Throughout the the
lifespan of Coconut Pre-Acquisition, we
were between 5 and 10, maybe at the very
most we had 12 content creators. And so,
we kept a very small team. I worked with
everyone closely. I met with everyone
one-to-one. I would say some of our
competitors and some people or some, you
know, founders that are building out
similar creator programs approach it
very, very differently. So, we always
had the mentality, great quote by Brian
Chesky who I look up to very much as
like a design background CEO. He says,
we want to build the the Navy SEALs, not
the Navy. And we had that approach with
our team overall and especially on the
content team. So, get to know every
single one of the creators, make sure
you spend time with them, make sure
you're enabling them with what creative
actually works and letting them know
what converts. And it's not a perfect
science, but when you have a video
getting 20, 30 million views, you know
what impact it has, right? Cuz you know
exactly when it's going viral and then
you can measure on those couple days
that it's going viral, what impact did
it have down funnel? And so I think it's
just a matter of like spending time with
the content team, making sure they know
what converts, what doesn't convert. And
at the end of the day, what we found is
that if you frame your product as a
novel toy, people are going to treat it
like a toy. They do not want to pay for
that thing. They are, you know, for
better for worse, I think people are
very entitled that if something digital,
it should be free. Right? Which is
probably subsidized by a lot of the
venture stuff built in the last 10, 15
years. But if you frame it as a solution
to a problem, then people are much more
willing to pay. It attracts a higher
willingness to pay customer. I know you
have a few stories related to that. Like
there's one video that got 41 million
views, 4 and 1/2 million likes, like
massively viral video, [snorts] but that
didn't convert. I mean, I I I'd imagine
you had quite a few of those. Any
lessons of like why that one didn't
convert specifically? I think it goes to
framing your product as a novel toy
and not a solution to a problem. So we
were experimenting with something called
pdf.brainrot.com,
which we've sent since sunset. And we we
kind of thought, or Brett put it in a
really nice way, it would be kind of
like a Trojan horse.
And so you can,
you know, picture this as, "Hey, I have
this really long PDF and I don't want to
read it." Or there's this really long
video or lecture recording, whatever it
may be, and I want to consume it in a
way that is, you know, more familiar to
me. And so we put a voiceover with a
background kind of Minecraft parkour
video. It was one of several things that
you could put in the background.
And uh, you know, true brain rot, it
gets roasted online, but people
absolutely loved it.
But one of the things that we
learned is that
that is a toy, and it's not something
that people are going to pay for. So I
think it has a place in a product suite,
but it's definitely not the thing that's
going to move the needle in terms of
revenue traction. Do you have this in in
coconut at all? Can I brain rot my PDFs?
Uh just like, you know, bespoke, nice,
tasteful brain rot. Do you know what I
mean? Like nature like a nature video
side by side or something like this?
It's not there right now, but you know,
I think we just need to tidy up some of
the product and we can we can bring it
back.
>> Has anybody I mean, this is off topic,
but has anybody done any like research
on this cuz like it just like took off
this like thing of like split screening
all these videos, right? I mean, I used
to work with a bunch of like animators
and stuff and they would always have
like a video up on the side. And like
the thesis I always had is like you like
you had something engaging a verbal
center, like listening to something or
watching something so that your drawing
center Yeah, I don't know if this is
real or not neurology, but this is
almost the inverse, right? Where it's
like have something engaging your visual
center, like your visual distraction,
whatever, so that your like verbal
center can like listen and actually take
in the content. We've slapped this like
brain rot label on it sort of like
which is it's funny, right? But like
there's probably actually some at least
a research worthy neurological benefit
to it potentially. Like if the people
like it, right? And there you go, you
just you're putting actual content in
there. It's like, you know, so what's
the harm, right? What's the harm? I do
think there's something there, Jacob.
I'll plug one of our drops, one of our
products in a feature is
speedreadit.com.
We saw a demo on Twitter X and it was a
way to read, you know, I would say
significantly faster than you can if
you're just reading a document or a PDF,
right?
>> I forget what the method's called like
where the word stays centered and then
like slides across. Exactly. And to your
point, Jacob, one of the things that
they do in the demo is they play
classical music in the background. And
so we kind of made our own, I think,
using 11 Labs and it's something that
occupies some part of the brain. And
you're right, absolutely be amazing to
have more scientific research on this,
but the intuition and the like observed
experience with this is very much if
some parts of your brain are satisfied
or occupied then you're much more likely
to be able to concentrate on something
else, right? Maybe the words that are in
front of you. So, we do a lot of
experiments like that. It's funny. Yeah,
the labeling of it as brain rot is like
maybe a disservice, right?
>> [laughter]
>> True. But it it is interesting that
those didn't convert well. You learn
those kind of lessons around what didn't
convert. Any takeaways from what did? I
mean, you know, you've you've shared the
high level, but like more specifically,
you know, were you better demonstrating
the product in the video? Were there
better hooks? Like what were the things
that convert? Cuz I mean, that's what's
so tough right now with UGC is to
actually
produce those like converting videos and
and hooks. Yeah, I think at a high level
you want to make sure that your product
is seen as a solution to a an existing
problem or as Brett mentioned, it
resonates deeply at an identity level.
So,
I am fit, therefore I'm going to use
Ladder as an example or I'm a runner, so
I'm going to use Runna or Strava. And
so, you want content that is more
identity focused, building brand
affinity within a certain audience or
market and or shows your product as a
solution to a problem. And those broadly
speaking are what we see the most at the
best conversion with. So much of what
you did was UGC and trying to go viral,
but did you take any of those videos and
turn them into paid and did you do any
paid, you know, as you grew? We tried
and we don't do it anymore. I think that
it's something that I would like to try
again, but
under our our model, you know, like what
would have been success for us was being
first first purchase profitable on the
ads and
we weren't able to get there. I think
that
looking back, you know, there it could
be part of like the
market that you're advertising towards,
but it also could be that I don't know
exactly. I'm curious what you think of
this, but I feel like neither of us like
took a ton of ownership there to really
like spend like more than half our time
or more than half our time on it. And so
we kind of just like slowly didn't get
anywhere and
if we did it again, I feel like we could
figure it out.
>> You kind of need I mean maybe not a
full-time person, but like I mean you
should always be kind of doing growth
and product all the same time, right?
And so you can split that uh maybe each
of you is doing half growth half product
or one person doing product one person
doing growth or engineering product
however you want to split it. But like I
always felt I've this very similar
experience for or uh performance
marketing. It's like Zack probably if
you didn't do the like creator
marketing, you probably could have
dedicated the time and got deep on it
and all that stuff, but I think that's
why I don't know how much this is true
now, but like you know, people shipping
an indie app and then the first thing
they do is like okay I'm going to set up
Facebook ads and like whatever and it's
like
you might not, you know, one the spends
you got to do to get the good data, the
attention it's going to take. It's like
that it should not be the first tool you
grab for. And I think I think UGC that
channel is much more controllable and
like much more um probably if you find
it much more efficient. I don't know
this might be true broadly for all
growth channels. Like there's very few
growth channels that you can half-ass if
you want them to work. Like you got to
really try, you know? Everybody's
trying, right? So if you're not trying
and like you're not going to you're not
going to be able to break through. Yep.
And if I would say if you're just
starting out and you don't know where
your customers hang out online, that's
bad news. Why would you start running
ads that indicates some lack of
fundamental knowledge that you should
have as a founder? Like if you don't
know where your customers are hanging
out online that that's that's bad news.
To Brett's question, it was certainly
under explored.
I think it's a hard we worked with some
very
good and solid people, but it's hard
outsourcing some things to an agency
because I think the incentives generally
speaking of an agency I heard someone
put it this way is like, you know, they
will do enough to keep you happy but
they're never going to be as invested.
And so I think aligning incentives in
some really sharp way around performance
marketing is a good idea.
One thing that surprised me
is we always thought you could just pour
fuel on the fire. So, those videos that
are getting 30 million views, let's
assume they convert well. Well, let's
just run ads behind it. Why would it not
work just as well? Surprisingly, that
wasn't really our experience that when
we worked with an outside agency to do
clips, so we would, you know, have
basically B-roll and raw videos that
were unedited from the same content team
that was posting and then we would
upload that into a a Google Drive and
share that with a like a clip agency.
They would chop it up and kind of make
something specific to performance
marketing that those as a creative that
could outperformed our more organic
approach. I found that really
interesting because I always assumed you
could just pour fuel on the fire. With
that said, we still really weren't able
to get um ads to work and it's something
that I think we can invest in in the
future. Targeting students, I imagine
made that especially hard. I'm honestly
surprised at the the whole story of
Coconote in that college students and
high school students are famously hard
to monetize. So, let's dig into how did
you get kids to pay for your app? And
what was the price and did you
experiment with pricing? Yeah, great
question. Definitely did a lot of
experimentation. I think we've tried to
always have something running. Um even
at launch we were testing like should
there be a free trial or not. The
college student archetype, I would say
didn't really like get to us. Like we
didn't want that to limit us from
charging a lot of money. Like we wanted
to be a premium product and be seen as a
premium product. I think that Zach and I
kind of just started product builders
who feel like we want to put something
out that has a lot of craft and charge
for it is part of it. Probably also like
not knowing what our costs would be is
what was also part of it. So, we put the
app out charging $99 per year and $19.99
per month. I think around like 80% of
people subscribe to the annual tier, so
we push that pretty hard. And I think
part of like the price too is
we want to be seen as premium so that we
also are seen as as reliable. I I kind
of like talked about it a little bit
earlier, but
there's a huge amount of trust you have
to gain to get someone to like stop
writing their notes and instead trust
that you will like take care of it cuz
they're going to have to be, you know,
taking an exam on it either way. And I
think that the premium feeling helps
with that to to believe that we're not
going to lose their recording.
>> Yeah, I think it's a I mean, I don't
know David, you probably have a better
sense, but just in terms of like the
utilities for students, not that that's
full what you guys are, but like that's
a high price point. I think the ones in
my head I can think of off the top it's
like third of that maybe for an annual,
right? Like 50 would be high. Which, you
know, I don't know. If it works, it
works, right? It's also nice that the in
terms of like not having
it being so levered on ad spend, right?
Usually allows you to go cheaper, but I
don't know. I mean, you're a bootstrap
company. It's better to have fewer
higher paying customers. It really is.
Maybe this was mentioned, but there's
there was no freemium, right? So, after
a week can I keep using it anyway or am
I done?
>> Yeah, you hit on a good few good things
there. You can make one note for free
without starting a trial and and that's
it. Basically a hard paywall, you know,
not quite, but like essentially a hard
paywall. Yeah. And and we even I mean,
one of our early experiments like we
launched at $99.99, but we one of our
early tests was raising it to $129 and
we saw the the magical like more users
and more revenues
at the same time. And so that's where
we've been for most of most of it. But I
do think we are one of the more
expensive options on the market and
to some of the
reliability stuff, like you can go into
the cheaper options and start recording
audio and like
get a phone call and lose your
recording, you know, like Apple does not
make it super easy to do this in a
reliable way. It's It's really not like
a
meeting note taker on Zoom where you
you like probably have perfect Wi-Fi and
your like computer is taking care of it.
>> based. Like you're actively engaged in
it, right? Like it's like PC mostly. I
mean, Zoom on the phone doesn't work
very well, right? It does have it suffer
from those things. Like if you get a
phone call or something, it'll kick you
out and cancel your video and things
like that.
>> Yep.
Yeah.
>> That's tricky. I did AV session audio,
whatever the Apple APIs for this are not
a dream. Uh having known from personal
experience. So
uh like getting those right. Uh
somebody's going to roast me cuz I
probably used the wrong framework name.
It's probably changed like five times,
but uh obviously like optimizing your
price testing, there's some of that. But
like most of your pricing authority just
comes from having a really good product.
You know, it's just having something
that like people will pay for and and
scarcity, right? It's like is there an
is there a comparable alternative? And
if the answer is no, you have a lot of
you know, really really great products
are hard to make, right? So if it's a
rare thing, if you made a really great
product, it's a rare thing, you can
charge a lot for it because it's just
not it's just not anywhere. I think
we've seen this in AI tools generally.
Like 2 years ago, there was only like
one model that was really really good
and they had a lot of pricing authority.
And now there's like other comparable
models, right? And we've talked about
the prices are going down, right? It's
like very classic economics supply
demand, which is interesting, too, cuz
did you see I'm sure somebody like
caught on to your guys' game and was
like, "Oh, we're going to make No no
notes." or something, right? Like
somebody trying to like fast follow you?
There's got to be hundred hundreds.
>> [laughter]
>> There's Coco note like with an R at the
end. There's There's one that's just
like a different fruit instead of a
coconut. There's all kinds of clones out
there. You know, I'm sure it impacts us,
right? But they are kind of just like
mosquitoes in a way, you know? Like
they're not taking themselves seriously.
I'm sure it impacts you, but it may may
not be a net negative, right? It may It
may be such that those are like lead gen
or like I do this all the time. Come in,
I have a need. I I try the premium app.
It's like a hundred and whatever. I'm
like, I just need it for like I just
want to try it. And then I go to the
second tier and I'm like, this sucks.
I'm going to go back and like try the
good one. It's not always directly
competitive, right? It's That's only
true in markets of a true commodity,
right? And apps
I don't even think there's any
exceptions. Like apps are not true
commodities, right? They can get close,
but like there's always some difference.
And And to some degree, commodities are
not true commodities, right? Unless they
pass through some very normal very
strong regulation process.
So yeah, I think like just generally
it's probably helps more than hurt would
be would be my guess. Cuz they're also
spending on ads probably, right? And so
like [laughter] And those users are
going to see that they're going to
search Coco Noter and they're going to
see you number two. And they're going to
be like, wait, this one looks less
sketchy. I wonder if some of that
pricing power also just came from
positioning and positioning it as a tool
for students. You know, we've talked
about this a lot on our podcast. Like,
you know, Ladder in the health and
fitness industry, they're charging $130
a year in an industry where it's $130 a
month to go to a nice gym and like $130
an hour for a trainer. And for college
students, I mean, paying 40, 50,
$100,000 a year to go to school and then
this is $130 a year. I I did see one of
your ads was like my friend's mom got
her this app Coco Not. Did you kind of
position it of like, you know, bug your
parents to help pay for this? Or Or like
was there any of of that that you did
find successful? Yeah, especially in the
early days, a good portion of our videos
that are going viral on our Instagram
were around, you know, my mom just
changed my life. And so, we did spend a
good portion of the uh the early days.
That's for other moms. That's not for
the student, right? Like you have a
student video that's like my mom changed
my life, and then you see other mom
being like, "Oh, I want to change my
bookum's life, right?"
>> That was very much the thinking. I mean,
the I used to say this to our creators
all the time. I said, "Imagine you're on
campus at, you know, student
orientation,
and you see a daughter and her mom,
right? And the daughter's just starting
college, and her mom's there with her.
And I said, 'Hey, I would like you to go
offer a a note-taker, something that's
going to help improve your grades, and
you know, make sure you never miss a
detail in lecture, etc. Help you study,
be a personalized study coach, etc.'
And it's $130 to do it. Who are you
going to ask? I think the obvious answer
is you're going to ask the mom, right?
And so, early on, we were very keen on
marketing to moms. I think we've since
like taken a step back. And by the way,
these are not mutually exclusive.
There's a big overlap.
>> It's finding who the buyer and the most
intent is, right? And you can have good
marketing to whoever might be in need,
right? I wonder how many app developers
get stuck down the route of like, "Oh, I
have to like advertise to the primary
user of the product, right?" And that
may or may not be the decision-maker in
a purchase. David, to your broader
question around monetization, just two
quick things to add on that are a little
bit higher level. One, great majority of
our customers are lifelong learners.
And so, they may be,  ,
non-traditional students. Brett and I
have talked to a lot of our customers
that are,
you know, not in the,  ,
traditional 18- to 22- or 23-year-old
college student age. They could be
studying for something that's not at an
accredited university. They could be at
a university, but outside of that age
range, any number of, you know,
derivatives there. Always amazing to to
talk to customers that are just making
it happen. Second thing is that I'm very
glad this again is not very tactical,
but I'm very glad we ignored
traditional, conventional wisdom.
I have a lot of, you know, smart friends
that if I would have gone to with the
idea for Coconuts, they would have said,
"Zach, no one's going to buy this,
right? You're targeting college students
that right?" And I'm so glad we did not
do that. I think in the early days of an
idea, you can almost imagine it like a
seed and you want to like shelter it
from a lot of harm, right? So that it it
can at least sprout. Because in
hindsight, it's like, "Oh, this was
amazing. Congrats." But only with the
benefit of hindsight did those smart
people say that. Whenever it starts out,
they will always gravitate towards the
reason it will not work. And I think a
much better framework is
what happens if it does work, right?
What impact can we have on our
customers? What economic value can we
create? Etc. So I'm very glad we did
that. Yeah, I mean, that's exactly why I
asked the question and what what I would
have thought externally, you know, just
having heard from so many. But it's like
I mean, it's like my app, a weather app.
Like college students are not going to
pay for a weather app. And so this a lot
of the conventional wisdom around what
people will and won't pay for is formed
based on totally different products. And
so when you come to the market with a
unique value prop, with a brand new
product that's enabled by AI in a way
that, you know, you could never create
this product before, it's like you
you've unlocked demand for that in a way
that nobody else had and can charge a
premium for it. So, yeah, it's really
cool.
One thing on there is like we are aware
that like it's expensive and that there
are there are students at the end of the
day and we want Coconuts to be available
to as many students as possible.
And it kind of goes back to what Zach
was saying earlier around being able to
think longer term under Quizlet and
stay tuned on on that, but I I think
that we'll be able to get Coconuts into
more people's hands in the future.
That's awesome. You know, one of the
keys in converting folks who saw this
UGC video is nailing the onboarding.
What were some of the lessons you
learned in, you know, getting people in
and convincing them of the value and
eventually, you know, getting them to
start that free trial? Yeah, I think
that there's kind of like a
like a meta at this point for consumer
apps of have a long onboarding and then
hit them with a hard paywall or
basically get someone to start a trial
within the first session, honestly, if
if not 24 hours. And
we have always had like a decent
onboarding, but we hadn't spent a ton of
time optimizing it. And we ran a test
trying to basically like double the
length. I think our onboarding is
15 screens or something. I remember when
we started talking to
Quizlet team, that's something that they
commented on. I mean, it really works.
Like it really works to get people a bit
more invested into what they're doing
and feel like it's more personalized,
show them some some social proof, and it
increased our trial start by 16%, which
we already felt like it was pretty good.
And so to continue to raise it was was
awesome. And it's one of those things
that continues to compound. What's funny
is
like as an engineer, whenever you start
a new product, you kind of like build
the login screen first and cuz you kind
of need it, right, to start playing
around with things. And
then it ends up staying there throughout
the rest of the the product. But one of
the nice things about being like there's
not always a lot of nice things about
being in
Apple and Google's walls, but
one of the nice things is you actually
don't really need to create an account
to make a purchase because you're
already signed into your Apple or Google
account. So, I think the biggest win
that we had was moving login to after
the paywall, basically at the end of
onboarding. It's very interesting. It's
like a there's some I think
revenuecat.com makes this pretty easy.
But that is tricky, right? Like being
able to take a payment before you have
an identity marker, being able to
associate those. Like there's a bunch of
plumbing we do to like make that
possible. And that introduces a lot of
complexity now cuz now and it but which
is there no matter where you put it is
that the like Apple purchase state and
the like the account state are like not
the same thing, which isn't the case
when you control the entire like
purchase payments flow like you would if
you were doing Stripe on the web or
something like this. It is a big
advantage, right? You know, users don't
have to think about it. You're not
pulling out a credit card. It's like
they know it's secure. Yeah, they've
kind of already done the double tap to
pay at that point. So, they'll double
tap to sign in. I think we were seeing
like 10% drop-off by having login being
the very first screen.
>> Were you capturing any contact details
before that? No, this this is just like
you download the app and open it and now
you're
forced to create an account. Well, once
people do start that free trial and it's
a hard paywall keeping them and having
them convert is that next big key. What
what were the unlocks there for helping
people convert and and any stats around
your trial start and trial conversion
rates that you want to share? I feel
like web and e-commerce have had like a
really big lead when it comes to the
stuff like the real like optimizations
and and the benefits of being like
outside of Apple's walls. Um It's more
like the wild west of what you can do.
Um We wanted to try some cancellation
flows there on our website and there's
like the standard asking questions about
why they're canceling, things like that.
And we were able to retain like 25% of
people from canceling, which we felt
like was pretty big. And to do that we
tried three things. One of them is like
your standard discount offers. You get
30% off if you stay or something like
that. Another one is pausing. So,
because we have students as our users,
they
come May or June, they don't want to
they don't want to keep paying over the
summer. And so, we thought we could try
pausing for 3 months. And then the last
one was trial extensions.
And this is one that I haven't seen that
much, but basically if you're on a free
trial and you go to cancel, then we
basically say, "Do you need Do you just
need more time?" And offer them 7 more
days. And that was the most successful
one by far. And it really keeps people
on that auto renew and I think it's so
hard to get them back onto auto renew
once they once they leave, but um
that was a big win for us and I think
there's a way to actually do this on
Apple and Google now, too. And so I'm
going to be um exploring that.
>> Apple does now have it's in it's in
limited beta right now and you have to
ask for it and get approved and
everything like that, but it's a
retention offers in App Store settings
like when they're actually outside of
your app trying to cancel, uh you can
now like show a screen and offer a
discount and things like that. I I don't
I actually don't know off the top of my
head what all you can do. I think it's
only a discount. I don't think you can
add additional trial. Are y'all doing
any of that inside the app as well? Like
do you have inside settings where people
go to to like look for cancellation
inside the app or or is that only on the
web that you're you're seeing those wins
and doing that?
>> It's only on the web. It's also in the
app if you subscribe through Stripe and
then we can just show it in a web view,
but yeah, that's the one that I still
want to bring to to mobile. Yeah, it's
harder to do with Apple payments, but
worth trying. Well, as we wrap up, I did
want to like actually talk through the
acquisition. How how did that start?
What was the the process? Did they reach
out to you? You reach out to them? Did
you talk to a banker about selling, a
broker? What was the process? Quizlet
actually reached out.
I would say we were only a few months
old and we were talking with Quizlet. I
remember when Brett first brought it to
me, he was like, "Hey, you know, someone
reached out. Should we take this call?"
And I said, "You know, I'd rather not.
Just say we're heads down building."
We'd been around for a couple months
like what could possibly come of that?
And uh I think Brett literally slept on
it and he came back and said,
"I'd really like to take the call. Like
let's just see what you know, what's
going on." I don't know. Some people
know what they want to do with the
company when they start it. Some people
don't. Was this like pre-discussed at
all? Did you be like, "Hey, we want to
build this and sell this. Hey, we just
want to see this. Did you have those
discussions or was did it was it more
open-ended? I would say we we had a
healthy outlook. We didn't have our
blinders on. We had conversations with a
handful of companies. Eventually, when
we kind of committed to going down this
path, it was taking up a good bit of
time. And that's, you know, the one
thing that I would say to other
founders, if you're getting inbound and
you're really weighing the options here
of acquisition, I would say make sure
you keep your eye on the ball cuz the
moment you take your eye off the ball,
they're going to you. That will reflect
negatively in the ongoing conversations.
We'll say that. And so, the the moment
we kind of said, "Hey, we're going to
take this seriously, but we want to keep
our energy focused on building and
growing the product." We worked with an
investment bank. We worked with a
partner named Chris Park at Accel
Partners, and they were really great to
work with. And then, they kind of led
the process from there. So, we actually
got in back in touch with Quizlet
through the investment banker. So, we
built a relationship with Quizlet, and
we we really loved I think there's a lot
of mission overlap for what it's worth.
Something that we haven't covered is
that Cocoa Notes' mission is to give
learners superpowers.
And that is not the explicit mission of
Quizlet, but I would say in spirit, it
is very, very similar, right? Learners
can be of all ages.
For me, one of the things that I love
about our mission statement is that we
acknowledge on the superpowers front, it
is intentionally vague.
The foundational LLM, you know, our AI
model providers are doing amazing work,
and we have no right to compete with
them. So, we want to recognize that, and
our job is to basically tailor the
foundational work that's being done, the
amazing foundational work, turn it into
a superpower for learners. And so, while
that isn't the explicit mission of
Quizlet, it's very much in spirit, I
would say, the mission in some way,
shape, or form of Quizlet. And so, we're
able to think much longer term. A lot of
things kind of overlapped, and
thankfully, the deal closed in December
of last year. Yeah, I mean, and I have
to imagine just having like mission
alignment also it's like I mean I have
to speak as a Quizlet user and like of
you know a watcher for a long time. It's
great company, right? They have good
brand, they have good products, right?
Uh makes it a lot easier to kind of
swallow the idea of like your baby going
some place else. Um and then obviously
like the integration work which I'm sure
you're doing now and like all of that
stuff is like, you know, it's not just a
dollar in very rare cases it's a dollar
a dollar is in a signature and it's
over, right? Like there's there's a
partnership that will take many years,
right? As this plays out. But like from
from okay, we're going to do this or
we're seriously thinking about it till
like close the deal, like how long did
that last for you guys? It was kind of
running in the background throughout the
year throughout last year. I mean
there's there's different like phases.
>> There's the talking phase, then there's
the Netflixing phase, right? Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. There's there's that but
also with the banker like the banker's
preparing things on their end and stuff
like that where we're not really like
actively doing anything and they're just
getting ready to reach out to people. So
it was um it felt like a long time to be
honest. That's a long time. Like your
whole company's two years in change,
right? So like
>> Right.
>> [laughter]
>> It's half of it.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Chris was kind of our
our third co-founder a little bit.
Uh [snorts] that's great. Tell me if I'm
cutting too deep but did you keep it to
between the two of you or did like the
rest of the team know or like how did
you manage that for that period of time?
Yeah. Yeah. We we kept it between us. It
felt like the kind of thing where you
know, we ourselves were not banking on
anything happening, you know? Like we
didn't want to feel like it was in the
uh anything like that and so we wouldn't
want to share it. Yeah, it's it's it can
be a real distraction. Like it's just
literally. Like you start counting your
money or whatever, you know, even if
especially if you don't know what the
deal's going to be shaped like, right?
You just start imagining and and
whatever. Yeah, I mean I'm sure for you
guys it was even if you managed it well,
probably take a lot of mental fortitude
to kind of keep it compartmentalized and
keep leading the business. And so you
you managed to keep growing through that
whole period uh that you're very happy
with. Yeah, totally. I don't think we
have the the metrics pulled up but but
revenue grew quite a bit. I would say
roughly doubled throughout that time.
Jacob, I think you you may appreciate
this. My wife didn't even know, much
less the folks on the team.
>> Wow, that's a commitment. I would never
be able to hold that line.
>> [laughter]
>> And so she yeah, she you know, she knew
we were talking with Quizlet, but she
had no knowledge of like, you know,
where the process stood. And so
>> Cuz you're like not letting it leak out
of part of your mind, right? You're just
being like keeping it compartmentalized
and be like, "Hey, this is just this
little thing. I'm not going to treat it
like a thing until it's real, right?"
And getting a spouse overly, you know,
excited and like it's hard enough as an
individual not letting it distract you
of like, "Oh, the money's coming." And
like, "What am I going to do with the
money?" Or like, "Oh, it's going to be
such a relief." I mean, there's so many
like emotions tied into it. And then
with another person, then all their
emotions get tied into it. Any baggage
they have about like money and security
and everything else like that. Like it
it's a very
emotional thing.
>> Okay, Zach, did they find out like after
close? Like there was some point that
you told them that this deal was going
to happen, right? You checked you
checked.
>> they still don't know.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, have you told them? Are they going
to find out on the pod? From the pod?
Yeah, well, I wouldn't send her the Sub
Club pod. I'm kidding.
>> [laughter]
>> It's not really your bag. Um the story
is uh it's it's pretty funny. We were
driving from uh North Carolina, so it
was right before the holidays. And uh we
were driving from North Carolina, where
I'm from originally, so we were visiting
my family up to Connecticut to see my
wife's family. And I was day one of the
flu, so I felt terrible. It was one of
the worst drives of my life. So uh yeah,
you know, Brett and I were talking and
uh we were kind of waiting for for
things to really close, i.e. the the
wire. And so yeah, when it happened, I
pulled over into a Taco Bell parking lot
and I told my wife and uh we celebrated
with Taco Bell. She cried by the
>> the that was the first moment she'd
heard of it. She was familiar, but she
wasn't familiar with like where things
stood. So, she knew something was, you
know, going on. She, you know, she knew
we flew out to San Francisco, met with
the Quizlet team. A lot of people
listening to this podcast I'd say
everybody has a life outside of Sub Club
podcast and their silly little apps. Do
you know what I mean? Like and and like
how those integrate in these these
things? Like the spouses and the people
around us, like they influence the stuff
and like how we interact with them
really matters and like your psychology
bleeds into their psychology and back
and forth and and I and I think it
doesn't get talked about much. Like most
people not many people have been through
this. Early on I started reaching out to
you know, founder CEOs to talk about M&A
process and and it kind of how they
handled it, how they thought about it.
People that have been through it you
know, successfully whatever. And one of
the best pieces of advice I got is, you
know, I think a great leader shelters
other people. And so, people on the
team, our engineers, content creators,
they didn't know about it until the day
of close. It's not that we were
withholding information because we
didn't want them to know. It's that we
wanted to shield them. Nothing happened
yet. And these things fall apart in the
last week.
>> Totally. signal to noise. And I think
it's the same thing, you know, with my
wife that it was just like a signal to
noise. I wanted to shelter her from
that. But I think the way, you know, she
reacted was a very was very much like
The Founder. If you guys have seen that.
The McDonald's movie.
>> Exactly. Clearly we're not, you know,
Coconut's not McDonald's, but I think
there was there are similar emotions
from going through it, from failing time
and time again, and to finally having
something that a lot of people dream of,
and to be partnered with a company like
Quizlet. It's a really fantastic moment
to share. How's your lives been
different like mentally as founders
stuff like pre and post? Like maybe in
in ways you expected and maybe in ways
you didn't. On my side, I think I focus
on my health more.
I'm not a parent yet and hopefully that
is in my future for my wife and I, but I
assume parents have a similar mentality
where you take care of your baby, you
take care of your child more so before
you take care of yourself. Like you can
go without and your baby is the one that
you want to see flourish.
And, you know, I guess it's probably the
best analogy that that Coda note was my
baby, our baby, not to be weird Brett,
but you know, it's like a it's something
that you care so deeply about that you
make sacrifices with yourself. And
unfortunately, I had some weird like
health things come up in the last couple
years and I more or less ignored them,
but I think I've been able to focus on
them more.
>> debt in the software world, right?
>> You took a little debt on your health
debt. It's a real thing. I mean,
especially if you know there's like some
sort of like liquidity event or maybe
not, some sort of event, some sort of
thing that's like like one way door, you
know, those trade-offs make sense,
right? I think the similar calculation
for people who are holding for a long
time, like that's also important, right?
If you if you didn't sell, if it wasn't
going to change the operating model and
how you guys are operating, at some
point you'd have to address that, right?
Whether or not the company sold or not,
right? So, it just kind of changes the
timing on on these things, which I guess
kind of fits into Zach, the point you're
making earlier about like just how it
allows you to change your outlook. Like
being sort of like attached to a larger
larger organization, I'm sure there's
obviously synergies between the products
and like those very interesting
collaborations to go on, but also just
having like being attached to a larger
resource pool like lets you be a little
more ambitious, lets you be a little
more like long-term and stuff like that,
which I think it's that's the bull case
for selling to a a good a well-aligned
company, right? It's like you can
actually
you are actually hoping to have a net
net market positive merger, right? So,
that both parties are actually worth
more like after it. Um and those are
some of the reasons why. Right. If there
is a wave of M&A with AI native apps,
very few founders will be able to talk
about the deal terms, be it they're not
comfortable or I would say more likely
because they don't want the corp dev's
team or whatever the acquirer doesn't
want
that information out there. There's lots
of reasons for both parties to not talk
about it.
>> Yeah. So, it's very understandable.
Yeah. I still think it's great that you
guys and I've been sharing with us and
and other founders too and and things
like this cuz yeah, I mean Zach, you
kind of hit on it. Like you can as a
founder, you can go out and find the
stories if you know and you can network,
but like it's it's I don't think talked
about enough.
>> Yeah. As this is just such a niche
topic. Like there's probably
a couple thousand people
for whom will go through this experience
in any given period in the shape that
you guys have have gone through. But I
mean obviously like many people listen
to this podcast aspire to do that and do
it's one path, right? And I think there
won't be another story quite like
Coconut, but there will be others that
that are similar, right? And so it's
good to get these written down and and
out there. Yeah. Yeah, thank you so much
for sharing. I think this is a great
place to wrap up. You know, what a what
a great story and and thank you both for
like being so open to share.
>> Did I say congrats at the beginning?
Like congrat- what a what a coup.
Congrats to both to Quizlet as well. I'm
sure they're listening. Like what a get,
you know? Good for them. Good for you
guys. Anything else you all want to
share as we're wrapping up? I know being
part of Quizlet now, he's probably had
some
more people you're wanting to hire and
things you're wanting to do with the
app. Anything you want to shout out
there? Yeah, yeah, sure. I mean first
thank you guys so much for having us on.
We're huge fans of everything that you
guys do. Zach and I are part of Quizlet
and Quizlet's hiring across product,
design, engineering, all of that. I
specifically think that I I'm hoping I
can find an iOS engineer out of this
podcast.
>> the a great audience for that, right?
Yeah. Should meet my friend Codex. Uh
he's very good at it. Yeah. So I'm
continuing to work on the Coconut
engineering team, but also the
subscription growth in general at
Quizlet. And so if anyone is interested
in coming and building paywalls for
Quizlet, we're one of the biggest
premium consumer apps out there. We've
got we can run experiments that add a
million dollars of revenue per year and
it's a lot of fun and we're looking for
for iOS engineers.
Well, congrats again and thanks so much
for joining us. This was a lot of fun.
Appreciate y'all. Thank you guys. Thank
you.
Thanks so much for listening.
If you have a minute, please leave a
review in your favorite podcast player.
You can also stop by chat.subclub.com
to join our private community.